Good morning church!
Congregation: Good Morning!
Hallelujah!
Congregation: Amen!
You may be seated.
Thank you
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We are going to talk about a very, very important issue.
It has to do with relationships.
Natural, I mean, human relationships, are very, very important.
That is why we are here today.
I am talking to you.
Here and now.
Because you are there, listening to me.
If you are there listening me, you cannot come here. I would be talking to the air.
Viewers at home, I say I am talking to you because I believe you are there, listening.
Paying attention to me.
I want to thank you, thank you for that.
Today's message is: Let God release you.
Tell your neighbor!
Church: Let God release you!
In your business!
Church: in your business!
In your relationship!
Church: In your relationship!
Regular relationships, such as marriage, business, even friendship, can break out of sheer circumstances.
Just like that.
The origin of relationships is God.
Until God releases us, we cannot quit the relationship.
But today, it does not take us anything.
Just disagreement, misunderstanding, conflict, and we quit a relationship.
You cannot do it alone.
You keep quitting relationships: business partners, marriage, friendships.
You move from one church to another.
Just like that.
It doesn't take you anything.
Without God releasing you, when are you going to settle with relationships?
That is the question you need to ask yourself.
When are you going to settle with the relationship?
You can count how many business partners you have had in the past.
Friends.
And the Bible says relationship begins with who?
With God.
And then to humans.
Relationship begins with God, and then to humans.
If a relationship begins with God, we cannot just quit from it under any circumstance.
Something that you are not the origin of, you can't just quit under any circumstance.
Unless you are released, you cannot just quit from it.
And you know, God can speak through disagreement.
God can speak through conflict, through tribulation, and adversity.
God can speak through them.
He can speak joy through sadness.
If God does not release us, and we quit the relationship
because of disagreement, because of misunderstanding,
because of conflict, whatever, the way you quit is the way you will enter the next relationship.
Unless you are released.
We don't leave a relationship as Christian because of fights.
Because of disagreements, because of conflicts, or adversity.
We don't leave relationships because the man that is your enemy today, can be your savior tomorrow.
Look at many of you that are in the church today.
You know what you have said about this ministry before now.
Or what you have done about this ministry.
But today, you are here.
Let me quickly take you to the message from the book of John 20, verse 23.
John 20:23
"If you forgive anyone's sins, their sins are forgiven.
If you do not forgive them, they are not forgiven."
What the Bible is trying to say here is that, if you forgive the sins of any, they are forgiven.
But if you retain the sins of any, they are retained.
This means, we preserve the sins of other people when we pick up an offence, and harbor resentment.
It is impossible to establish a healthy, a good relationship
with a person who has left another relationship resentful and offended.
Someone who breaks a relationship because of misunderstanding or conflicts -
now becomes your friend?
There is no friendship there.
You are destroyed.
Come.
This is my brother.
We are friends.
But something happens and we start fighting.
Hey!
I don't know what happened.
You are foolish!
Maybe I am wrong, or maybe I am right.
Or you are wrong, or you are right.
We have no right to go with that conflict and establish another relationship.
If we now decided not to come together, and I now have another friend here.
This man is in trouble because the relationship we are going to establish is purely disease, affliction.
Because he has a broken relationship here- misunderstanding or disagreement that is unsettled.
But now you are now my friend.
And you too, you might have had your own, somewhere, and we come together.
Can you see the reason why we are facing relationships that are neither lasting nor rewarding?
This is why you end up with relationships without reward.
Because you fight this one, and you end the relationship.
And look for another friend.
Remember: You carry conflict, hatred, bitterness, offence, and become the friend of another person.
And the person, too, may also have a broken relationship somewhere.
And now the two of you are together.
Can you see the life we are living?
You cannot succeed alone. You need people. You need friends.
Jesus knew this. That is why He had disciples.
You will not be able to succeed alone.
It is impossible to establish a healthy, a good relationship,
with a person who has left another relationship bitter and offended.
You can never have a healthy relationship.
A rewarding relationship.
This is why today, when you see a broken home,
a divorced woman or man, marrying someone who is also divorced, at least 90% still divorced
Because the carryover they have where they are coming from.
If God releases you, you would not be under pressure to judge.
To be under pressure is to be under the control of our circumstances.
Allowing situations to control, mislead, and overwhelm us.
If you are released, you will go with joy, even in the face of adversity.
For a good example:
You know that attending church is a thing of God.
But today, someone just brought you here today.
Someone told you there are miracles here.
That is why you are here.
Someone just told you that a woman you have been looking for, for many years
is attending Synagogue Church.
That is why you are here today.
Someone just told you that your chairman is a member of the Synagogue Church.
Someone told you that the man you are looking for a contract from, is a member of this church.
That is why you are here today.
Attending church is a thing of God.
When we go to church, we are answering God's invitation.
Do not leave under any circumstance because it is God's invitation.
Don't pull out of the church or a relationship under any circumstances.
Like disagreements, misunderstanding, taking offence.
Whether you are right or wrong.
We should let God release us.
We should let God do what?
If God releases you, even in the face of crisis, you will go with joy.
In the book of Isaiah 55, verse 12, it says you will go with joy.
Every Christian should realize that where God wants them to be, the devil will want to offend them to pull out.
If you are in a place where God wants you to be, the devil will want to offend you to pull out.
The devil is always interested in where God wants you to be!
Where God wants you to go!
Where God wants you to sit!
What God wants you to say.
The devil is interested in it.
Anytime you wake up, and you are going to business, and you start receiving an attack, or some accident happens, don't give up.
Continue to go there.
Anything close to Jesus receives attacks.
If your relationship with your wife or friend is being attacked,
or if your business is being attacked so much, know that this is where God wants you to be.
If you are in a place where God wants you, the devil will want to offend you to pull out.
You have abandoned a business that would have put you on the world map because of attacks.
You have abandoned a relationship that would have built your future and your career because of attacks.
You have abandoned...
Oh my God.
Think of the many things you have abandoned because of attacks, and threats, to your life.
A business that would have put you on the world map, you abandoned it because of too much debt and loss.
You abandoned it.
That is where and what God wants you to do. The devil knows and that is why he attacking you.
You abandoned something that would have changed your life.
The business that would have changed you forever, you abandoned it because of attacks.
A friend that would have helped you, because of conflict, or trouble, you abandoned that friend.
Wives, a place that would have changed you forever, you stopped because of attacks and trouble.
Think about that. The enemy? Who is that enemy? You are the enemy of yourself.
Why can't I abandon the Synagogue Church of All Nations with all that has been happening to me?
How do you know what you are doing now is the right thing or where God wants you to be?
Don't try to make it easy for the devil.
You are making it easy for the devil.
Stay where you are!
Don't budge.
Stay where you are.
In times of great conflict, stay where you are!
Don't budge!
Don't make it easy for the devil.
You are making it easy for the devil.
You are making it so simple for the devil to get what he wants.
This is a common problem.
This is why we do not wait patiently for God's release.
Rather, it is trouble that releases us from the relationship.
It is trouble that releases us from our marriage.
It is trouble that releases us from our business partners.
Think back about your journey, then you will know.
We do not wait patiently for God's release in our regular relationships.
Rather, it is our circumstances that release us.
This is why we are always facing relationships that are neither lasting nor rewarding.
You cannot succeed alone; you need people.
But to get good people, you must work through bad to get good.
My Bible made me to understand that when you are looking for good
you cannot find it just by mere stretching your hand.
My Bible made me to understand that you walk through bad, worse, bad, worse,
before you can find good.
This is why the Bible says: "find out the truth".
You must do some work before you can get the truth.
To get the truth you must get through alot before getting the truth.
Find out the truth and the truth shall set you free.
It does not say: "get the truth".
As Christian, we should see situations such as conflict, hurt,
all forms of offences as God's way to strengthen our character.
Tell your neighbour.
See situations such as conflicts, hurt, all forms of offenses as God's way to strengthen our character.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Situations should not release us from our regular relationships.
See what situations have done in your life.
It is the situation that destroyed your marriage.
The same situation that destroyed your business.
Because of fight, disagreement.
He is a thieve, foreigner, a criminal... This and that. He has duped you.
If he has duped you its not enough for you to leave the business.
Stay and get used to the situation – the situation will mature you.
Our situations are tests to mature us.
The SCOAN Sunday Service [claps]
Let go of your past.
Let go of this moment because another moment is coming.
If I am going this way, this direction
whatever I encounter on my way going, I should let go, because I am going to meet another moment.
Every moment, let go.
This moment when somebody slaps me
OK, I am not going to stay there, I am going forward, to another moment.
I should let go, so I can deal with this moment.
I am going, they see me going. What happens at this moment? Somebody hits me.
OK. Do I still want to go? If I still want to go forward, I should let go this moment,
because if I don't let this moment go, and I move to another moment;
and somebody slaps me, and I still carry this slap of yesterday today again, it means...
You know what it means when you have a carryover.
It is not a good thing, a carryover in your school assignment. It is a very bad thing.
Since you know you cannot succeed alone
you cannot do without a friend, you cannot do without a business partner. It is not possible
Even our Lord, Jesus Christ knew this; that is why He had 12 disciples.
He had His disciples and distributed assignments for them
because He knew He would not be able to succeed alone.
So, there is nothing you can do alone.
If there is anything you can do alone - let me know.
So, you need people.
When I say you need people, I mean you need good people.
But to get those good people you go through bad, before you get the good.
And if you are looking for that good, you do not want to deal with bad people
but just looking for good ones - you can never get it.
Because the Bible says: "find out".
The SCOAN Sunday Service.
No matter what are you going through in your relationship,
remember that relationship begins with God.
If the relationship begins with God,
it means no matter what you are going through, it should not release you from that relationship.
LET GOD RELEASE YOU
If you had been waiting patiently for God to release you all this while,
I know, the sky would have been your limit.
Many things you see as bad, behind the bad, there is good.
A friend you see as a bad guy, is the saviour God sent to rescue you tomorrow.
He may be bad today but tomorrow he is another person.
LET GOD RELEASE YOU
Let God what? (Church response): release you!
Look at many marriages today.
It was this great crisis or conflict that separated many marriages.
And yet, they have not met the loved one they were looking for.
Ask anyone who is in this situation and they will tell you that they are managing.
Tell your neighbour, "They are managing".
We are dealing not only with the hurt which took place in the new relationship
but also with the hurt from the former relationship.
Tell your neighbour: we are dealing not only with the hurt that took place in the new relationship
but with the hurt from the former relationship.
Two hurts – the way you left this relationship, the way you will enter the new relationship.
It is a carryover. That is life.
The hurt of the former relationship and the new one are together.
I know that you will be very surprised to hear this from me.
The business that would have turned you around, you abandoned it because of circumstances.
A friend that would have helped you in life, in the past, you abandoned because of adversities.
Can I ask a question?
How do we have a healthy relationship?
We know that it is impossible to establish a relationship with a person
who has left another relationship bitter and offended.
It is impossible to establish a relationship with a person
How does this message appeal to you?
Thank you.
How does this message appeal to you Sir?
(Response): Usually there will be a lot of carryovers.
The temptations is always there to judge the new relationship
with the mistakes of the former relationship.
And this always brings bitterness.
Such things in fact, I witnessed a marriage,
where the new wife,
whatever she does, the husband always says
why are you behaving like this other woman again?
Always remembering the experiences of the past marriage.
It's like a multiplication of the effects.
It's not the best. That's my advice.
Thank you Sir.
Lets hear from you, Sir.
(Response): First of all, I must confess the sermon today is for me.
From the start to the end.
Yesterday I arrived from Sierra Leone and even before I came to the Synagogue, I have been praying.
Sometimes I tried to come but I didn't have time to come.
I had other engagements.
The marriage aspect has to do with me.
The business aspect has to do with me as well.
The business aspect is even recent.
The marriage aspect... I just want to say, from the time the man of God entered here,
what I asked God for is what he is telling me. So, I want to thank God.
It's really excruciating.
You cannot compare it to anything else in this world. Not even losing money.
When you lose a relationship you have strived so much to keep.
Clap for him. Thank you very much.
Lastly, which I want you to go over again.
Harbouring offences too long without forgiveness,
the result is a life of self-imposed isolation, self-centredness and total caging.
How do we know that we have not forgiven?
You say you have forgiven.
But how do we know you have not yet forgiven?
In a little time, you will talk and refer to the issue.
You keep referring to your loss but you never refer to your gain.
we know you are harbouring an offence, without forgiveness.
Tell your neighbour: you keep referring to your loss; you never refer to your gain.
You keep referring to your failure; you never refer to your success.
Harbouring offences too long without forgiveness,
the result is a life of self-imposed isolation, self-centeredness and total caging.
Tell your neighbor: you keep referring to your loss; you never refer to your gain.